It's beautiful.
It's the $10 million Nightscape,
after all.
I wish we all could've gotten to see it.
-Yeah.
-That's true.
My locked memories...
started flooding out unchecked.
Kids. Congratulations on graduating.
We had some good times.
We had some sad times.
We had successes and failures.
So much happened.
You may be graduating grade school today,
but there's still much you lack.
That goes for me, too.
But life is about filling
these voids inside of us.
That's my belief.
In my other memory,
Kayo, Hiromi...
and Aya Nakanishi had all been killed.
I could've...
I could've saved them.
That's right.
I had a past where I failed.
And this present exists
because I did it over.
I've probably lived
the same amount of time twice.
This?
Kumi made this for you.
How long...
have I been asleep?
One year and two months.
It's May...
2005.
Good morning, Satoru.
Stop making me repeat myself, you dummy.
Sorry.
JULY 5TH, 2005 (TUESDAY)
My memory is still in fragments,
with important pieces missing.
I need to get them back
as soon as possible.
Airi...
Satoru.
I hear your operation was a success, Kumi.
I'm happy for you.
Thanks. I wasn't scared,
because you helped me.
Although, that was over a year ago.
Oh, right.
Oh, thanks for the crane origami.
I was so surprised.
You just collapsed over there.
Are you here for a checkup?
I'm totally fine now,
but they keep treating me like I'm sick.
They told me to stay inside
over my summer break.
I didn't even have plans.
I want to go camping.
Hey.
Was that always yours?
This? It was a gift.
Do you remember?
There was this girl who punched out
some weird camera guy.
Her name is Airi.
Airi...
The moment you awoke,
so did the urge inside me.
Overlapping memories...
Yeah. The memories feel so real.
In the memories where I didn't sleep,
Kayo, Hiromi, and Aya were all murdered.
It's as if I repeated my life.
I see.
I sound crazy, don't I?
Let's assume you're not.
What about the killer?
Were you able to remember anything?
No, not yet.
I can't remember anything
from right before it happened.
I see.
Is there anyone you suspect?
There is.
But I won't tell you.
You have the right answer
locked inside you.
I don't want to influence you
and risk giving you a false memory.
I'll wait.
By the way...
don't we always have secret meetings
in stairwells?
Do we?
Yeah, we do.
I can't let things end like this.
Hooray, I woke up,
now I'm just going to let it go? No.
I'm going to get back my memories.
COURTESY OF THE NISHIFUNABASHI
CITY COUNCIL
CHIBA CENTRAL HOSPITAL
Mr. Nishizono.
The grant increase we just received
can be directly attributed
to the years
you've spent laying the groundwork.
Sir, perhaps you'd consider entering
either a mayoral or congressional race.
To me, success is...
being involved on the ground level,
somewhere near the everyday citizen.
That's why I don't need any more
than this city.
My ambition...
lies somewhere else.
Meeting Airi helped me recover some
of my memories of the future.
I'd like to see her again.
But how?
How are you? You feeling okay?
Yes.
All right.
Dr. Kitamura.
I'd like to take a trip tomorrow.
Could I have your permission?
In my professional opinion,
I don't think you're ready.
Yes, sir.
But I want to try to find any leads
that will help me recover my memory.
This wasn't my patient...
but there was a track athlete
who broke his leg below the knee.
And so, they decided
to stabilize the break with a rod.
Doctors told him to rest
and recover for two months,
then go through
another four months of rehab
before he would be able
to walk normally again.
But there was a competition coming up
in four months.
He wanted to go.
And so, he threw himself into his rehab.
Oh, of course we stopped him.
Because rushing the rehabilitation process
could risk lingering aftereffects.
Did he make it to the competition?
Your rate of recovery...
is even faster than his.
It defies medical explanation,
and you could say
it's almost supernatural.
So, he didn't make it.
Does that worry you, doctor?
No.
Personally, I have a good idea what it is.
There's this troublesome thing out there
that easily disregards all the hard work
and analysis we do as doctors.
-Do you know what it is?
-No.
Human will.
Human will?
Yes.
That's why...
if you feel like it's okay,
then it probably is.
I'll give you permission.
Thank you very much.
Oh, and by the way,
that track athlete.
He made it to the competition...
and won.
I'm going to go see her.
I need to move forward with my own feet.
I'm sure my legs still remember
where she is,
and they'll take me to her.
Hey.
Stop.
Wake up!
Oh, you're awake.
Do you know who you are
and why you're here?
Thank goodness.
I live close by.
Why don't you come with me?
Have a seat.
There's no way you killed your mother.
Let me just get you some money, then.
Everything in front of us
is still in progress.
The end is still far into the future,
and nobody knows what it is yet.
Airi.
She was the only one who believed me.
I remember now, Airi.
I remember you were someone important
to me.
Airi.
I'm sorry. This is all my fault.
The kidnapping and murders
of those young girls in Hokkaido
have all passed
the statute of limitations.
The only one
for which statute of limitations isn't up
is the June 2001 murder in Chiba.
But...
that murder was a little different
from the others.
Nobody has been arrested.
Maybe the police just didn't make it
to the suspect the killer set up.
No. It's hard to imagine
he'd make such a mistake.
Maybe it's simply unrelated.
Satoru? What is it?
Got it. I can bring it by. See you.
What did Satoru want?
He wanted to borrow my graduation book.
I see.
-Well, no sense trying to rush things.
-You're right.
Hey, Young Kobayashi.
Drink with me.
I'm not that young.
Good, Young Kobayashi.
I said, I'm not that young.
-What's wrong, Young Kobayashi?
-Just went down the wrong pipe.
They're doing it again.
Looks good.
SASANQUA GET TOGETHER
Ms. Sachiko.
Hey there, Kumi.
What do you think about this?
A barbeque and fireworks?
They do it every year.
Did you know about it?
They put the posters up every year
in the Pediatrics wing.
A mixer for the patients.
I've been to this camping site
on a field trip, and it was beautiful.
I think it'd be good for Satoru's rehab.
Right, Satoru?
Satoru.
Weren't you listening?
Let's go do this together.
Looks fun, right?
It does.
Maybe I'll go.
Yes. Let's totally go.
You know, Ms. Sachiko,
you can see Mount Fuji from there.
-Mount Fuji? Really?
-Yeah. You can see Mount Fuji.
Hello.
Hope I'm not intruding.
Here.
Let's all go past the hill
Whistling all the way
The sky is blue and clear
Guiding us to the farm
Let's all sing
A cheerful melody
You must be so happy, Ms. Fujinuma.
Satoru is finally able
to participate this year.
I really am.
I've dreamed of this day.
Oh, how I've dreamed of this day.
Show me, Satoru.
Give me that thrill and exhilaration.
FUJI DRIVE
Subtitle translation by
Zensho Yamamoto